Guide to the Union for Radical Political Economics and Review of radical political economics records, 1961-2013.
Union for Radical Political Economics and Review of radical political economics records, 1961-2013
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Union for Radical Political Economics and Review of radical political economics records, 1961-2013.
3791
Union for Radical Political Economics.
35.4 cubic ft.
Correspondence, minutes, printed material, financial and administrative records, scholarly papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence, memoranda, editorial board minutes, and other records of the Union for Radical Political Economics (URPE) and of its publication, the "Review of Radical Political Economics" (RRPE).
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The Union for Radical Political Economics (URPE) was founded in 1968 by graduate students and faculty from the University of Michigan, Harvard University, and Radcliffe College. The organization promotes an interdisciplinary approach to political economics that considers political science, sociology, and social psychology. URPE's annual activities include a winter meeting as part of the Allied Social Science Association (ASSA) and a summer conference. URPE publishes a quarterly journal, "Review of Radical Political Economics" (RRPE), and a bi-monthly newsletter.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence, memoranda, editorial board minutes, and other records of the Union for Radical Political Economics (URPE) and of its publication, the "Review of Radical Political Economics" (RRPE). Other acronyms commonly used in the collection include American Economic Association (AEA), Allied Social Sciences Assocations (ASSA), Steering Committee Monthly Reports (BAG).
SUBJECTS
Names:
Union for Radical Political Economics.
Titles:
Review of Radical Political Economics.
Subjects:
Economics.; Radicalism.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to all unpublished materials not related to the screening of articles for the "Review" restricted for 15 years from the date of creation, except with permission of the author.
Access to all unpublished materials related to the screening of articles for the "Review" restricted for the lifetime of the parties involved with the correspondence except with permission of the parties involved.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
Series I. Articles Submitted for Publication in RRPE
Boxes 1, 2, 5, 14, 20-23, 26, 27, 33, 34
Series II. Articles Submitted for Publication to Specific RRPE Issues
Boxes 2, 3, 15-20, 24,25
Series III. Editorial Records of RRPE
Boxes 3, 6, 14, 32
Series IV. URPE Records 1969-1986
Boxes 4, 41
Series V. Publications
Boxes 4, 6, 7, 41
Series VI. The Review of Radical Political Economics (RRPE)
Boxes 6, 7
Series VII. Summer Conference Papers
Boxes 6, 8, 9, 41
Series VIII. Other Conferences
Box 6, 10, 41
Series IX. URPE Steering Committee
Box 11, 41
Series X. URPE Records and Miscellany
Boxes 5, 6, 10, 12-14
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Articles Submitted for Publication in RRPE
  Includes a copy of articles submitted for publication, correspondence between the author and the editorial coordinator of that article. [Note: Folder titles consisted of the author's last name and a brief title. These have been completed wherever possible.]
  - Ackerman. "Income Distribution in the U.S." (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Agosin, Manuel R. "Assumptions, Value Judgements and Ideology in the Concept of 'Economic Man.'" (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alperovitz, Gar. "Towards a Pluralist American Commonwealth." (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Anspach, Ralph. "Micro-theory, Macro-theory and Man as a Factor of Production." (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Arak, Marcelle and Cohen, Bruce. "Students, Selective Service and Self-interest: Some Empirical Findings." (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Barkin, David. "A Cuban Strategy of Development." (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Barnett, Bill, "The Effects of Consumer Bliss on Welfare Economics." (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bates, Timothy. "Economic Origins of Political Power in America." (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Beckwith, Burnham P. "A Comment on Bergson's "Market Socialism Revisited.'" (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Behr, T., V. Garlin, J. Morris and R. Roehl. "The Necessity of a Radical Political Economy." (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Block, Walter. "Free Market Anarchism and the New Left." (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Block, Walter. "On State Banking." (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Blumenfeld, Emily. "Millet and Madden on Engels." (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bowles, Samuel. "Class Power and Mass Education: The Beginnings of A Study of Social Structure and Educational Policy." (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bruyn, Severyn T. "Social Change Within the University." and "The Future of the American Economy; Real and Ideal Images." (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Campbell, William F. "Orthodox and Radical Political Economy." (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Ciscel, David G. "Productive and Unproductive Labor: A Sketch." (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Cole, Robert E. "The Economics of Privilege." (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Cole, Steven A. "The Psychological Costs of Capitalism and Industrialism." (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Cornoy. "The Political Economy of Education." (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Cypher, James M. "A Note on the Application of Intellectual Obscurantism to the Theory of Imperialism." (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Cypher, James M. "The Liberals Discover Militarism." (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Daly, Herman E. "A Pedagogical Deflation of Price Theory." (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Denny, Michael. "A Reconstruction of Economics: Comments on Shubik and Bronfenbrenner." (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - de Vroey, Michael. "The Measurement of the Separation of Ownership and Control in Large Corporations - A Critical Review." (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - de Vroey, Michael. "Une Explication Sociologique de la Predominance du Paradigme Neo-Classique Dans la Science Economique." (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Diwan, Romesh. "The Climate of Opinion in India." (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Dowd, Douglas. "Galbraith's Political Economy; Or, Idyll with Feet of Clay." (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Dowd, Douglas. "The State and the Industrial Revolution." (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Droucopoulos, Vassilis, "Marxist vs. Bourgeois Economics: The Great Depression." (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Du Boff, R.B. "The Effects of American Foreign Investment." (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Edwards, Richard. "Who Fares Well in the Welfare State." (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Fatemi, Ali M.S. and Van Fleet, David D. "An Empirical Study of Black Capitalism and Ghetto Development." (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Faulhaber, R.W. "To Each According to His Need, Personal Development." (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Faulhaber, R.W. "Economie et Humanisme's Search for a Human Economic System." (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Fleischmann, Mr. William. "A Note on Spectra Precipicism in the Political Economy of Inflation." (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Franklin, Raymond S. "Party and Class-State and Revolution." (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Frech, H.E. "Exploitation by Regulation: Occupational Licensure and Medical Care." (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Fried, William. "Electrical Generation and Land Use." (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Fusfeld, Daniel R. "The Political Economy of Tight Money." (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Gambino, Ferruccio. "Labor - Power, Capital, and State at Fords of Dagenham and Langley." (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Gindin, Sam. "A Note on the Political Economy of Pollution." (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Gintis, Herbert. "Neo-classical Welfare Economics and Individual Development." (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Gintis, Herbert. "On Commodity Fetishism and Irrational Production." (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Gintis, Herbert. "Towards a Radical Welfare Economics." (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Goldberg. "Depressions." (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Goodstein, Marvin E. "Who Gets What; Poverty Under the Market System." (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Gordon. "Class and the Economics of Crime." (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Gottschalk, Peter T. "Surplus Value from Neoclassical Analysis?" (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Grabosky, Peter N. "Organizational Impediments to Diversification of Aerospace Industry Films." (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Griffith, John R. "Some Economic Implications of Court Congestion." (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Halbrook, Stephen P. "Maoism and Economic Decentralization." (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Hardesty, John. "The Macroeconomics of Environmental Destruction." (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Havrilesky, Thomas. "Technological Innovativeness and the Competitive Ethic." (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Herman, Edward. "Notes on Corporate and Banker Control." (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Herman, Boerg. "On Necessity in Political Economy." (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Hirschman, Larry. Review of "The Agony of American Left" by Christopher Lasch. (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Hope, Kempe R. "Cooperative Socialism in Guyana." (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Horvat, Branko. "Economic Science and Economic Systems." (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Hossein, Hamid. "Colonialism and Underdevelopment." (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Huizer, Gerrit. "Is Our Research in Underdeveloped Countries Justified?" (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Junt, E.K. "Simon Nelson Patten and the New Deal." (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Irons, James. "The Correct Description of The Multiplier." (cont.) (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Jhunjhunwala, Bharat, and Vinod Vyasulu. "Toward an Elemental Interpretation of Social Institutions." (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Kauri, David E. "Community College Vocational Programs and Economic Opportunity for Minorities." (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Kelkar, V. "A Study in the Political Economy of Economic Development; Comparative Performances of India and China." (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Kruchnic, Richard. "Raytheon Company: Heart of the Massachusetts Military-Industrial Complex." (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Labinski, Paul F. "The Capitalist System as an Urban Problem." (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Landsberg, Martin. "Mechanics of the International Monetary System." (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Langlois, M. "Economics, Radical and Mineral." (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Lee, George. "Marxism, Imperialism and the Third World." (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Leibsohn, Dan. "Spatial Relations in Community." (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Lippitt, Victor. "A Critique of Comparative Economic Studies." (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Lorber, Neil M. "The Case Against Laissez-Faire." (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Mac Ewan, Arthur. "Contradictions in Capitalist Development: The Case of Pakistan." (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Mac Ewan, Arthur. "Capitalist Expansion, Ideology and Intervention. " (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Mac Ewan, Arthur and Edwards, Richard C. "A Radical Approach to Economics: basis for a new curriculum." (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "Some Notes on the American Working Class." (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Mandel, Jay R. "The New Insurgencies: An Economic Framework." (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Mandel, Jay R. "Post-Revolutionary America: The Economics of Liberation." (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Martin, David. "Beyond Positive Economics: Toward Moral Philosophy." (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Melman, Seymour. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Mermelstein, David. "Ecological Armageddon: A Comment." (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Merrett, Steve. "Political Economy of Complicity." (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Meyer, Peter B. "The Underlying Objectives of the United States and Their Implications for New Economic Order." (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Miller, S.M. "Social Policies for Revolutionaries." (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Moskoff, William. "The Mis-Education of the Industrial Corporation Executive." (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Meilson, Richard. "Advertising Regulation and Economic Growth." (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Newton, Jan. "Political Economy of Womens' Oppression." (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Nikolinakos, M. "The Concept of the 'European South' and the North-South Problem in Europe." (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Nisbet, Charles T. "Economic Rationale and Economic Effects of U.S. Private Investments in the Third World: An Appraisal of Marxian and Non-Marxian Methodology." (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - O'Conner, James. "The Fiscal Crises of the State." (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Ollman, Bertell. "Alienation and the Law of Value." (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Pares, Rhonda L. "The Overemployment Problem." (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Peet, Richard. "Poor People of the Rural Periphery." (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Perry, Steward E. and Frankena, Mark W. "Land Title for the Alaska Natives and Their Economic Development." (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Phillipoff, Robert. "Comment on RRPE Vol. 1 No. 1" (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Pluta, Leonard. "A New Approach to Welfare Economics." (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Pollard, Vincent. "Three National Health Proposals: Taxation and the U.S. Working Class." (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Pool, John. "Introductory Economics and the Radical Textbook." (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Pool, John. "Reform versus Revolution: The Radical Dilemma." (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Poole, Lee. "Comment on Gintis." (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Posner, Bob. "The Rise and Demise of Capitalism, or the Perilous Road to the Nebulous End." (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Powers, Edward J. "A Contribution to the Theory of Economics Writing: Classicism Revisited." (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Powers, Edward J. "Humor and Economic Dissent." (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Rosenberg, Leo O. "Florida is a Nice State to Own." (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Rosenblum, Simon. "The State in Capitalist Society." (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Sackrey, Charles. "Economics and Black Poverty." (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Sackrey, Charles. "The Elusive Economics of the New Left." (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Sackrey, Charles. "A Note on Women's Liberation." (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Sangha, K.S. "Keynes versus Underdevelopment.: (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Sawers, Larry and Weaver, Jim. "The U.S. Economy in 1980." (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Sawers, Larry and Weaver, Jim. " Report on the Washington URPE Conference." (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Sawers, Larry. "Review of The Urban Transportation Problem." (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Sazama, Gerald and Villarroel, Juan R. "All Power to the Students!" (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Scroggins, Jim. "Review of Greening of America." (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Shaw, Philip. "The Privileges of Monopoly Capitalism: Market Power in the Ethical Drug Industry." (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Sherman Howard. "Review of Alienation." (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Snowbarger, Marvin. "A Suggestion Regarding the Rolde of Referees." (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Stamos, Stephen C. "A Production Approach to Consumer Behavior: Educational and Ecological Liberation." (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Standfield, Ron. "Limited Capitalism and Neo-Marxism." (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Stevenson, Gelvin L. "A Simple Income Distribution Game." (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Stutsman, Douglas. "A Simple Explanation of the Inflation/Unemployment Dilemma." (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Stutsman, Douglas. "A Case for Wage and Price Controls." (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Surkin, Lourdes B. "Review of The Capitalist System.. ." (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Surkin, Lourdes B. "Economic: A Positive or Normative s Science." (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Szymanski, Albert. "Imperialism and the U.S. Working Class." (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Tabb, William K. "The Black Ghetto as Colony." (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Thompson, Herb. "The Ghetto Economy: Reform of Revolution." (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Thurow, Lester C. "The Elimination of Poverty." (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Tilman, Rick. "Pluralist-Elitist Debate." (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Turgeon, Lynn. "Foreign Aid." (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Turgeon, Lynn. "Income Policies at Home and Abroad." (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Wachtel, Howard M. "Statistical Noise and the Voices of the Poor* Poverty, Human Capitalists and Economics Systems." (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Wagner, Frank E. "Economic Liberalism: Midwife of Imperialism." (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Ward, Lorne, "The Monopoly Capitalist Origins of Inflation and Unemployment." (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Weaver, James H. "Toward a Radical Political Economics." (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Weisskopf, Thomas E. "Capitalism, Underdevelopment and the Future of Poor Countries." (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Welty, Gordon. "Technological Rationalism and the View of the Future." (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Yunker, James A. "Investment Propensities Under Capitalism and Market Socialism." (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Zaremba, Arlene. "The United Trust Company in Guatemala ..." (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Zimbalist, Andrew. "Dependence and Underdevelopment in Chile." (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Zweig, "Towards a Radical Political Economy." (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Zweig, Mike. Book. (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Bechtold, Brigitte. "Beyond Hardin and Ostrom: New Heterodox Research - The Commons" (Box 36, Folder 43)
  - Ackerman, Frank. "One Dismay Science Meets Another" (Box 36, Folder 44)
  - Carroll, William. "Robust Radicalism" (Box 36, Folder 57)
  - Weisskoff, Thomas. "Reflections on 50 Years of Radical Political Economy" (Box 36, Folder 58)
  - Bechtold, Brigitte. "Neoclassical Economics and Federal Policies" (Box 36, Folder 59)
  - Sherman, Zoe. "Pricing the Eyes of Passersby: The Commodification of Audience" (Box 36, Folder 60)
  - Orhangazi, Ozgur. "Capital Flows and Credit Expansions in Turkey" (Box 36, Folder 61)
  - Arab Spring (Box 36, Folder 62)
  - Full Employment (Box 36, Folder 63)
  - Subseries A: "Other rejections."
    - 1971 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - 1973 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - 1973 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - 1998 (Box 27, Folder 23-66)
    - 1998-2002 (Box 28, Folder 1-64)
    - 2001-2003 (Box 29, Folder 1-76)
    - 2002-2005 (Box 30, Folder 1-70)
    - 2004-2009 (Box 31, Folder 1-78)
    - 2007-2010 (Box 32, Folder 1-77)
    - 2009-2010 (Box 33, Folder 1-7)
    - 1996-2011 (ASSA) (Box 33, Folder 8-74)
    - 2011-2013 (ASSA) (Box 34, Folder 15-22)
    - 2008-2013 (Box 34, Folder 23-105)
    - 2009-2013 (Box 36, Folder 64-84)
    - 2013-2014 (Box 37, Folder 1-47)
    - 2014-2015 (Box 38, Folder 1-48)
    - 2014-2015 (Box 40, Folder 1-73)
  - Subseries B: Numbered Articles Submitted And Accepted, (originally submitted to specific RRPE issues)
    - #1226 - Michl, Thomas. "Three Models of the Falling Rate of Profit", 1994 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - #1256 - James, Vanus. "Surplus in Lewis's Theory of Development", 1994 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - #1259 - Levy, Paul. "Redistribution-The Market's Overhead", 1993 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - #1275 - Nilsson, Eric. "Capitalist's Institutional Agenda", 1994 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - #1280 - Meurs, Mieke. "From Hoes to Hoes", 1993 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - #1297b - Reviewed by Reati, Angelo. "New Developments on Structural Change and the Labor Theory of Value", 1993 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - #1323b - Reviewed by Lembke, Jerry. "Celebration of Work", 1995 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - #1330 - Endo, Koshi. "Sex and Union Member Discrimination Under the Satei System in the Japanese Firm", 1997 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - #1332 - De Angelis, Massimo. "Social Relations, Commodity-Fetishism and Marx's Critique of Political Economy", 1996 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - #1336b - Reviewed by Lee, Frederic S. "Beyond Competition: The Economics of Mergers and Monopoly Power", 1996 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - #1350b - Reviewed by Holt, Richard. "The Pathology of the U.S. Economy", 1995 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - #1356b - Reviewed by Mouhammed, Adil. "Silent Depression: The Fate of the American Dream", 1995 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - #1357b - Reviewed by Bechtold, Brigitte. "The New American Workplace; Transforming Work Systems in the United States", 1994 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - #1361b - Reviewed by Maurer, Bill. "Fidel! Castro's Political and Social Thought", 1995 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - #1363b - Reviewed by Maas, Harro. "Spectres of Marx", 1995 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - #1366 - Screpanti, Ernesto. "A Pure Insider Theory of Hysteresis in Inflation and Unemployment", 1996 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - #1371 - Kalmans, Rebecca. "Productive Activity, Accumulation and Growth in Postwar Japan and the United States", 1996 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - #1382 - Doucouliagos, Chris. "The Comparative Efficiency and Productivity Performance of Labor-Managed and Capital-Managed Firms", 1996 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - #1384b - Reviewed by Wells, David. "Women's Employment and the Capitalist Family", 1996 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - #1392 - Goldstein, Jonathan. "The Empirical Relevance of the Cyclical and Secular Profit Squeeze: A Reassertion", 1996 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - #1393 - Lavoie, Marc. "Traverse, Hysteresis, and Normal Rates of Capacity Utilization in Kaleckian Models of Growth and Distribution", 1996 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - #1396 - Mohun, Simon. "Productive and Unproductive Labour in the Labour Theory of Value", 1996 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - #1401b - Reviewed by Swanke, Thomas. "The General Will: Rousseau, Marx, Communism", 1997 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - #1407 - Meurs, Mieke and Morrissey, Monique. "Agricultural Ecology and Changing Economic Systems: Lessons from the Bulgarian Case", 1996 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - #1408b - Reviewed by Perelman, Michael. "John Bates Clark: The Making of a Neoclassical Economist", 1996 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - #1409b - Reviewed by Bechtold, Brigitte. "Bringing It All Back Home: Class, Gender and Power in the Modern Household., 1996 (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - #1413b - Reviewed by Wilson, Tamar Diana. "The Strategic Silence: Gender and Economic Policy", 1996 (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - #1421b - Reviewed by Lee, Frederic. "Competition, Technology and Money: Classical and Post-Keynesian Perspectives:, 1996 (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - #1430b - Reviewed by Reifer, Elisha. "Rhetoric and Marxism", 1996 (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - #1435b - Reviewed by Andrews, David. "Keynes's Philosophical Development", 1996 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - #1438b - Reviewed by Mouhammed, Adil. "New Directions in Analytical Political Economy", 1996 (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - #1440b - Reviewed by Yaghmaian, Behzad. "The Chase Across the Globe: International Accumulation and the Contradictions for Nation States", 1996 (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - # 1448b - Reviewed by Lovell, Vicky. "Who Pays for Kids?, 1996 (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - #1451c - Sherman, Howard. Comment on "Theories of Cyclical Profit Squeeze, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - #1454b - Reviewed by Richards, Donald. "Silent Revolution: Rise and Fall of Market Economics", 1996 (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - #1456b - Reviewed by Brown, William S. "The Chicago Plan and New Deal Banking Reform", 1996 (Box 20, Folder 36)
    - #1457b - Reviewed by Fusfeld, Daniel. "Heterodox Economic Theories: True or False?", 1996 (Box 20, Folder 37)
    - #1458b - Reviewed by Lambert, Thomas. "World Economic Primacy: 1500-1990", 1996 (Box 20, Folder 38)
    - #1459c - Houston, David. "Comment on Simon Mohun's Productive and Unproductive Labor in the Labor Theory of Value", 1996 (Box 20, Folder 39)
    - #1460 - Sheehan, Maura; Hamilton, Douglas; Munck, Ronnie. "Political Conflict, Partition and the Underdevelopment of the Irish Economy", 1997 (Box 20, Folder 40)
    - #1461b - Reviewed by McDermott. "Cold War in the Working Class: The Rise and Decline of the United Electrical Workers", 1996 (Box 20, Folder 41)
    - #1464 - Cornwall, Richard. "Deconstructing Silence: The Queer Political Economy of the Social Articulation of Desire", 1996 (Box 20, Folder 42)
    - #1469b - Reviewed by Lanciaux, Bernadette. "The Politics of Oligarchy: Institutional Choice in Imperial Japan", 1997 (Box 20, Folder 43)
    - #1470 - Thompson, Frank. "The Composition of Capital and the Rate of Profit", 1997 (Box 20, Folder 44)
    - #1476b - Reviewed by McKinney, Scott. "A Model Development Plan: New Strategies and Perspectives", 1997 (Box 20, Folder 45)
    - #1477b - Reviewed by Koritz, Douglas. "Long Waves of Capitalist Development", 1996 (Box 20, Folder 46)
    - #1479S - Dickens, Edwin. "The Federal Reserve's Tight Monetary Policy During 1973-1975 Recession: A Survey of Possible Interpretations", 1996 (Box 20, Folder 47)